Hendra Kurniawan

hendrakurniawann46@gmail.com | +6287840491199 | https://www.linkedin.com

PROFILE

Hendra Kurniawan, an experienced individual in the manufacturing industry, has a diverse work history. With 3 years of experience working in Japan as a CNC Machinist in a company specializing in the production of mold plates for car components, Hendra then transitioned to a role as a Maintenance Automation Technician at PT Panasonic Industrial Devices Batam, a Semiconductor manifacturing company, where he worked for 2 years. Currently, he is working at PT Sumitomo Wiring Systems Batam Indonesia as a Design Development. While studying at Batam State Politechnic and committed to continue learning and growing in his career.

EDUCATION

Batam State Polytechnic

Batam, ID

 $Bachelor\ Degree\ , Electronic\ Engineering\ Technology$

Present

PCB Design, Internet of Things, Mechanical Design GPA 7 Smester : 3.65/4.00

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

IoT Engineer, Automation Development, Design Development, PCB Design, Prototype Modelling

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: C++,Python

Software: FluidSIM, CX-Programmer, EasyEda, Visual Basic Studio, IDE, Fushion360, Inventor, AutoCad, SolidWorks, Office, Excel.

EXPERIENCE

PT Sumitomo Wiring Systems Batam Indonesia

Batam, ID

Development Design

October 2023 - Present

- Supporting the work of Japan Sumitomo Development Department
- Project Planner For New Product Trial
- Analyze the Wire Harness manufacturing process for Productivity Improvement, Quality, and Cost
- Interpreter

Design Engineer

June 2023 – September 2023

- Checker for new design Wire Harness
- Incharge of new product trials
- Analize manufacturing process and material that can reduce the cost of making Wire Harness without damaging quality.

PT Panasonic Industrial Devices Batam

Batam, ID

June 2021 – June 2023

- Maintenance Automation TechnicianIncharge Line Production
 - Analyze and troubleshoot any abnormalities in products and machine
 - Mantaining productivity and line efficiency
 - Maintenance

エムケイケイ株式会社/MKK Co.,LTD

Ama City, JP

Computer Numerical Control Machinist

April 2018 – April 2021

- Incharge for 3 CNC Milling Machine & 1 CNC wirecut
- Setter for tools and product
- Maintenance
- Trainer for Japanese New Employee

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Smart Door Lock System using Eye Movement Detection

July 2024 - December 2024

Machine Learning

Developed a smart door lock system using Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for authentication through eye movement detection. The system processes eye images, trains a CNN model, and evaluates reliability and responsiveness.

Rent Car Guard, Internet of Things

February 2023 – July 2023

Internet of Things

This device improves rental car security with a speed alarm that triggers a buzzer and sends notifications when speed limits are exceeded, GPS tracking to monitor location, and an engine cutoff feature if the car isn't returned within 24 hours, reducing risks of theft, damage, and accidents.